Sincro: wyxchari
This is a preliminary warning. Preliminary warning. Prepare phase one base evacuation procedure. Phase one evacuation.
这是一次预警, 这是一次预警。请做好一级撤离准备, 一级撤离
...determine the extent of breakdown factor in ionisation...
...正在计算离子化进程崩溃的影响...
Why has the ioniser been allowed to deteriorate to danger level?
怎么能够让离子器降到这么危险的程度？
There was a power stoppage. I've done all I can to boost it.
刚才有个能源中断，我已经想尽办法来恢复了
Well it can't be allowed to fall any lower.
不能再让它下降了
We still have time to evacuate.
我们还有时间撤离
We will certainly not evacuate. We've beaten its tantrums before.
我们当然不撤，我们驯服过它的臭脾气
It's falling again.
它又下降了
Well hold it... steady
抓紧...稳住
I can't.
我做不到
Switch the stabilising circuits through to the computer.
通过电脑打开稳定回路
I have, it's still not holding!
我打开了，但还是稳不住
All circuits, woman, all circuits!
所有线路，女人，都打开
We're nearly there.
差不多了
There's not enough power.
没有足够的能量
It's slowing down.
它在减速
Maybe it'll hold there.
可能就稳在这个位置了
I doubt it.
我有点怀疑
Well, at least it gives us time.
至少给了我们一点时间
We need Scientist Penley.
我们需要科学家Penley
He is no longer a member of this post. You will make this machine work.
他已经不是这个站的一员了。你要把这个机器搞定
Yes, Leader Clent.
好的，Clent 组长
That's better.
这还差不多
Emergency evacuation phasing set?
已经进入了紧急撤离状态？
Yes.
是的
loniser state fault check?
离子器的失效检测系统呢
Yes.
是的
Reactor safety sequence in operation. Good.
正在按反应器安全规程操作。很好
You'll make an organiser first class yet, Miss Garrett.
你会是个一流的组织者，Garrett小姐
I only follow your example, Leader Clent.
我只是照你的样子做而已，Clent组长
What is the latest report from all other ioniser bases?
其它那些离子器基地的报告怎么说
All bases are in phase. America: glaciers held. Australasia: glaciers held. South Africa: glaciers held. Asia: some improvement claimed.
所以基地都已有进展在了。美洲: 冰川已稳住。澳洲：冰川已稳住。南非：冰川已稳住。亚洲：取得部分进展
They would!
他们还真行
Britannicus Base, Europe: slipping out of phase. Glacial advance imminent.
欧洲不列颠基地: 濒临失控, 冰山马上就会继续前进
If we fail, the whole program for glacier containment is in danger.
如果我们失败, 这个冰川控制计划就危险了
I'm fully aware of that fact.
我很清楚这个情况
But in two hours, the ioniser will be useless.
但再过两个小时, 离子器也将很快失去作用
And then the glaciers will move again... 5000 years of history... crushed beneath a moving mountain of ice.
然后冰山就会再次移动...五千年的历史啊...毁在一座移动的冰山上
Phase two evacuation. Emergency. Phase two evacuation. Red state emergency. Red state emergency.
进入二级撤离状态。紧急通告。二级撤离, 红色紧急状态, 红色紧急状态。
Priority override.
越权调整优先级(?)
Yes, of course. But Penley was the expert.
好的。不过 Penley 才是这方面的专家
I've had enough of experts. Their crazy ideas. Where's Arden?
我受够这些专家了, 还有他们疯狂的想法。Arden 哪里去了?
Still at the ice face, completing the instrumentation project.
还在冰面上呢, 设备注入工作还没有完成
Well, hasn't he been warned?
那, 有人传达告警信息吗？
We couldn't get through...
我们不可能熬过去的...
Well we have to tell him, immediately! I cannot lose any more men!
但我们必须告诉他, 马上！我不能再失去任何人！
Leader Clent to Scientist Arden at glacier face, come in Arden!
组长 Clent 呼叫冰面上科学家 Arden, 请回话!
Walters, through here. Now clear that...
Walters, 到这里来。现在清除这里...
Sir. Get your drill ready, Davis.
准备好你的钻孔机, Davis
Sir!
头儿
Yes?
怎么?
Come quickly, Sir!
快过来, 头儿
I could swear there's something inside.
我发誓这里面有某种东西
Oh, not another mastodon.
哦, 别又来一头长毛象
Well look for yourself, Sir.
诺你自己来看啊, 头儿
Is it a man?
是不是一个人?
Perhaps it's an animal.
也许是个动物
Well we'll soon find out. Davis, the heavy drill.
我们很快就能搞明白。Davis, 拿大钻来
Yes Sir.
好的头儿
Base calling, Sir.
基地呼叫呢, 头儿
What do they want?
他们想要怎样？
There's nothing coming through. Poor reception. I suppose they might...
没有具体内容传过来, 信号太差了。我猜他们可能。。。
They'll have to wait. This is more important. Come on Davis.
那让他们等一等, 这个更重要。来吧, Davis
Well what are we going to do, Sir?
我们现在打算做什么, 头儿？
Do? Excavate. This could be a brilliant discovery.
做什么, 凿开啊。这可能是一个巨大的科学发现
But Sir - the computerised schedule! We must stick to that.
但是头儿, 电脑制定的时间表怎么办？我们必须及时赶上啊
Oh, must we?
哦, 必须吗？
Leader Clent will be furious, Sir.
组长 Clent 会咆哮的, 头儿
Well that's just too bad. For once we'll do something on our own account, eh?
那就太糟糕了哈。但这一次我们自己决定吧, 怎样？
There's not much base can do about it Sir, after all, we can't even ask permission, can we?
基地也不能拿我们怎么样, 头儿。毕竟, 我们没法征得他们的同意啊, 是吧
Come on Davis, hurry man!
来吧, Davis, 快点
Arden, for heavens sake. man, come in! This is urgent!
Arden, 老天, 伙计, 快回话。正在紧急关头啊
_ again. _ is decreasing. Not far from total disintegration.
?? 又出现了。?? 正在下降。估计不久就会完全解体了
Arrgh!
啊
What's the matter?
怎么回事
You're on my head!
你踩到我头上了
Careful!
小心啊
Come on, Victoria. Give me your hand.
快上来, Victoria, 把手给我
It was a blind landing.
这次着陆是一个“盲降"
Is that what you call it?
那是你发明的词？
Well no broken bones. Hey, look at the snow.
嗯, 没有折断骨头。嘿, 看看这雪景
Oh no, not again! Tibet was bad enough, but I think you've put us down just further up the mountain!
哦, 不要, 别又是这个。西藏还不够糟吗。不过这次我猜你把我们带到山上面来了
Well let's see, shall we? Very careful, I'm going to get out. It's quite a long drop.
那, 我们来看看, 好不。小心点, 我打算出去。还真是一个??
Come on Victoria, that's right.
来吧 Victoria, 就这样
Hey, looks like a great big wall of ice. Look!
嘿, 看起来是一道巨大的冰墙, 快看
Ooohhh!
嗷嗷
What is it?
怎么了
You're on my hand!
你夹到我的手了
But Doctor, look.
博士, 你看
Yes, that's not ice, that's plastic.
看到了, 那不是冰, 那是塑料
Yes and, see how smooth it is, and curved.
是, 不过看看它多平整, 还是曲线型的
It's a dome. A protective dome.
这是一个穹顶, 一个保护性的穹顶
It's so big. Can't see the end of it. Wonder what's inside.
可真大啊, 都看不到边。好奇里面都有什么
Don't worry, those alarms weren't meant for us. I wonder what's wrong, though.
别担心, 那些警报声不是针对我们的。我猜什么地方出问题了
Ach, that's their problem. Come on.
啊, 那是他们自己的问题, 走吧
Leader Clent! The video! Arden has made contact.
组长 Clent, 有视频了！Arden 联络我们了
Arden! Can you hear me?
Arden, 你能听到吗？
Yes. What is it?
是的, 什么事？
You must return to base immediately.
你们必须马上返回基地
Well don't panic. I've almost finished setting up the seismograph probe. Davis hurry up.
没有必要恐慌, 我们这里地震探测器已经快装好了。Davis, 快一点
Well... the ioniser's nearly at disintegration point.
只是... 离子器快达到解体程度了
Oooh, I wonder if Penley's ears are burning.
哦, 我想知道 Penley 的耳朵有没有烧起来
It's not a laughing matter, man! You know what it means.
这不是一件可以开玩笑的事, 你知道这意味着什么
Yes, cold weather ahead. I thought it felt a bit nippy.
是的, 这里可真冷啊, 我都觉得有点刺骨了
There'll be a full enquiry into your delay, you realise that.
会有一个完整的临讯会, 关于你进度落后的问题, 你明白吗？
Yes, and I've got a very good reason. A fantastic discovery, in the ice.
明白, 但我有一个很好的理由, 一个奇妙的发现, 在冰里发现的
Your task was to set up movement probes in the ice, not indulge in amateur archaeology.
你的任务是在冰里面安装运行探测器, 不是搞些业余的考古
This is a man!
里面有一个人
Well, congratulations. Makes a change from fossils. Now leave it and return.
那就恭喜你, 从化石中得到了新发现。现在别理那个, 赶紧回来
I'm bringing the body back with me.
我们把这据尸体也带回来
Arden.
I'm sorry, I can't hear you. There seems to some interference.
对不起, 我听不见, 这里好像有些干扰
Arden!
Oh, Doctor, it's just like my home.
哦, 博士, 这里就像我的家一样
I know!
我知道
Red state emergency. Evacuation phase three. Phase three evacuate. Transport section leaders report now. Phase three evacuation.
红色紧急状态, 进入三级撤离阶段, 三级撤离。运输部组长立刻报告。进入三级撤离阶段
Something's wrong.
出了什么事了
Seems safe enough.
看起来挺安全啊
Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你
Thank you. Excuse me Miss, I'm Jamie McCrimmon, do you think you could tell us where we are?
谢谢你。对不起小姐, 我是 Jamie McCrimmon。你能否告诉我们这是哪里
She doesn't want to know, Jamie.
她似乎并不想知道, Jamie
Hey, this says we're on evacuation flight seven.
嘿, 上面说我们分在第七次疏散航班
Yes, rather inhospitable, we've only just arrived!
是啊, 相当不好客啊, 我们才刚刚抵达
Mmm.
唔
Hey, and this tag, it says I'm a scavenger!
嘿, 这个标签, 上面说我是流浪汉
And yours does too! Hey, we're not beggars!
你的也是！ 嘿, 我们不是乞丐
Hush Jamie.
安静, Jamie
What is it Doctor?
怎么了, 博士
Sounds like electronic machinery, like a computer. There's something wrong with it's pitch.
听起来像是个电子设备, 某种电脑。它什么地方有点问题
Oh no. Now look, it might be dangerous, now let's leave it.
哦别, 你看, 这个可能很危险, 我们走吧
No.
不
Doctor.
博士
Let's go in.
我们进去
Oh, there's something very wrong here.
哦, 这里有什么东西非常不对劲
Now is _ still out of phase?... Seven-two point four...
现在?? 还没正常吗？... 72.4...
Seven-two point four? That's bad.
72.4? 那可不妙
Now balance those gauges, Miss Henry. 17 degrees out from normal.
现在把那些读数平衡下来, Henry 小姐。超出正常值17 度
17 degrees? Well this is serious!
17 度？ 这可严重了
One-three-seven-nine, no... Excuse me
1-3-7-9。不。。。打扰一下
Who the blazes are you? Get these scavengers out of here!
你是什么人？把这些流浪汉赶出这里
We're not scavengers!
我们不是流浪汉
Out of here!
出去！
No! In two minutes 38 seconds, you're going to have an almighty explosion! The readings say so!
不, 还有2分38秒你们就要有一场剧烈的爆炸了, 这些读数已经表明了
Well how do you possibly know that, I haven't even, I haven't even processed them through the computer yet!
呵, 你怎么可能知道这个？我都还没有, 还没有让电脑处理过这些数据
I don't need a computer!
我不需要一台电脑
If he's right it's already too late to escape!
如果他是对的, 那已经来不及逃走了
No it isn't, it doesn't have to happen, if you'll excuse me.
不, 不会的, 并不一定会发生, 如果你允许。。。
Cut out the reactor!
切断反应堆!
There's insufficient power for that.
没有足够的能量执行这个操作
Well a quick short burst then from the reactor unit, now.
那就从反应器单元接一个短脉冲过来, 快
Off!
切断!
Now link the circuit, with the reactor link.
现在接通回路, 用反应器连接
Now, bring in the computer stabiliser.
现在, 把电脑稳定器接进来
Yes, yes, that should hold it steady. It's a, it's not a perfect job, mind you. You ought to get an expert in, you know.
是的, 是的, 应该可以稳住了。虽然不算是非常完美。你应该搞一个专家来, 你知道吗？
How did you... It was all bluff, wasn't it, that two minutes 38 seconds to danger?
你怎么。。。你完全是在唬人吧, 是不是？ 2分38秒就要发生危险？
Oh no, it was near enough correct, give or take a second.
哦不, 很接近正确值, 误差不超过一秒。
Rubbish.
胡说
Check it on your precious computer, then.
那就用你宝贵的电脑核查一遍吧
Miss Garrett, do so.
Garrett 小姐, 照做
loniser fall rate: seven-two point four, ion compensator: minus one-seven degrees, ion flow rate: one-three-seven-nine. Assessment please.
离子器失效率: 72.4, 离子补偿器: -17度, 离子流速: 1-3-7-9。请评估
Immediate emergency. In two minutes 37 seconds, the reactor will explode.
立刻进入紧急状态。在2分37秒内, 离子器将会爆炸
Well a second out. We... can't all be perfect.
啊差了一秒。。。但我们不可能那么精准
We're at half power now, Leader Clent!
我们现在只有一半能量了, 组长 Clent
Why even Penley couldn't have done better. Where on earth did you spring from?
即便是 Penley 也不能做得更好。你到底是从哪里冒出来的
It doesn't matter, look...
这无关紧要, 你看。。。
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, no no no no. It's nothing, it's just um, it's just an emergency _ and 10 hour duty spell.
抱歉, 抱歉, 不, 不。。。没事, 只是有点紧急。。。还有扛了10个小时的。。。
The vibro-chair.
按摩椅
Yes, you're right. Um, contact the Medi-Control Centre the moment there's a further _ We'll talk at the same time, come with me.
是, 你是对的, 唔, 联系医疗中心中心。。。与此同时我们谈谈, 跟我来
Ask him where we are!
问问他我们是在哪里
A giant among prehistoric men.
一个史前的巨人
See the kind of armour he's got on?
看到他身上那个盔甲一样的东西没？
Yes, that's rather strange. He looks pre-Viking. But no such civilisation existed in prehistoric times before the first ice age.
看到了, 很奇怪, 他看起来像是维京人的先祖。不过在第一次冰川期并没有这样的史前文明存在啊
Ha! Proper "Ice Warrior", isn't he, Sir? I reckon Leader Clent will be interested.
哈, 叫它”寒冰勇士“怎样, 头儿？我猜组长 Clent 会感兴趣的
Yes. What'll the mighty computer make of it, eh?
是的, 那个全能的电脑会分析点什么出来的, 是吧？
Sir, hadn't we better get back while the weather still holds?
头儿, 天气一直这样的话, 我们最好还是回去吧
Good point Walters. Davis, try bringing the air-sled a little closer, will you?
说得对, Walters. Davis 你去把气垫雪撬拿近一点, 好吗
What are they up to?
他们要去干什么
Arden's found something in the ice. Something to take back to Clent. It won't be appreciated.
Arden 在冰里面发现了什么东西, 要带回到 Clent 那里。不会得到表扬的
Ar, they ought to leave way alone.
他们应该别管这个
Arden was always a researcher. He wanted to be an archaeologist when I knew him.
Arden 始终还是一个学究, 我认识他的时候他就想当一个考古学家
Archaeology. What good's that?
考古学家, 那有什么好的？
It's good to know things, even when they're dead.
可以搞明白一些事情很帮啊, 即使是死了
Nothing's sacred to you, is it?
对你们而言没什么是神圣的吗
I only ask questions, it's in my character I suppose.
我只是不断提问题, 我想这是我的天性
Ar, you swore you'd give all that up.
啊, 你发誓你会放弃那个的
Discovery's as exciting to me as the hunt is to you. But with Clent, he uses scientists' craniums as stepping stones for his ambitions.
科学发现对于我来说是很激动人性的, 正如打猎对于你一样。不过对于 Clent, 他用科学家的头盖骨作为自己野心的垫脚石
Ar, that's about all you lot are fit for...
啊, 那就是你们这些家伙为什么适合。。。
Well we're not totally useless, surely?
我们也不是完全一无是处, 是吧
To me you are. Come on, we've got to move. Leave them to... stupid games.
对我来说, 你是的。来, 我们得走了。把这些。。。愚蠢的游戏留给他们吧
Avalanche! Come on!
雪崩了！快！
Where's Davis?
Davis 哪儿去啦？
Storr! Come on! Avalanche!
Storr 快过来, 雪崩了！
Storr, are you alright?
Storr 你没事吧
Penley...
What's the damage?
哪里出问题了？
My arm. It's gone I think.
我的胳膊, 我估计断了
Broken?
断了？
Feels like it.
感觉像是
Well you're lucky. There's one down there who's staying on the mountain for good.
啊, 你很幸运。有个家伙掉下去了, 只能长眠在山里了
They'll... they'll come looking for him. We must move out a bit. Unless you fancy trying to turn me over to your friends.
他们会。。。他们会来找他的。我们得往外面移一点。除非你情愿把我交给你的朋友们(?)
Six weeks ago they were my friends, but not anymore. Can you walk?
六个星期以前他们是我的朋友, 但已经不再是了。 你能走吗？
Aye. Just you try and keep up. Come on.
能吧, 你试试, 扶我起来, 来
All clear, Sir.
过去了, 头儿
Yes, but how 'bout Davis?
嗯, 但 Davis 呢？
I'll go look for him.
我去找他
Well let's hope he's safe. With another man gone, Clent'll skin me alive.
最好他安然无恙。要是又损失一个人, Clent 会活剥了我的
Well if he gets too difficult, you can always set your warrior on him, eh Sir?
哈如果他再找麻烦, 你可以打开你的寒冰勇士对付他, 对吧头儿？哈哈哈
But you've no valid proof of your qualifications?
但你没有什么材料证明你的资格吗？
Look, aren't we wasting time?
你看, 我们是不是在浪费时间？
If you want our help, why not tell us all about it?
如果你想要我们的帮助, 为什么不将所有情况都告诉我们呢？
All about it? All about what? Where have you been all these years?
所有情况？什么所有情况？你这些年都在哪里呢？
Well, er, as a matter of fact, we've, we've been in retreat. In, in Tibet. We are sanctifiers.
哦, 这个, 事实上呢, 我们撤退了, 到了西藏, 我们朝圣去了
Oh, I see. In Tibet. Well if you'll take a simple test, I'll soon know if you're up to our scientific standards.
哦, 明白了。去西藏了。这样, 如果你接受一个简单的测试, 我就很快能知道你是否能满足我们的科学标准
I see, and er, if I fail?
我明白了, 要是我没通过呢？
You'll be evacuated with the other scavengers in due course.
你会跟其它流浪汉一起疏散走的
Oh, where to?
哦, 去哪儿？
The African rehabilitation centres, of course.
当然是非洲定居点
Oh no, not Africa.
哦, 不要, 不去非洲
Very well, fire away.
那好吧, 发招吧
I present you a problem.
我给你一个难题
Yes.
好
All the major continents are threatened with destruction, under the glaciers of the second ice age.
所有的大陆都面临着碎掉的威胁, 因为第二次冰河世纪的冰山
Oh.
哦
How would you halt the ice surge, and turn the climate back to normal? 45 seconds, starting from... now.
你打算如何阻止冰山涌来, 把气温转回正常？45秒, 从现在。。。开始
Oh, er, ahem, er, possible causes, er, the reversal of the magnetic field.
哦, 嗯, 可能的原因是, 呃, 地球磁场反转了
No such change has occurred.
没有发生这样的事情
Um, interstellar clouds, er, obscuring the suns rays.
唔, 星际云层, 额, 遮挡了太阳光
An excessive burst of sunspot activity.
太阳活动突然爆发
A severe shift of the Earth's angle of rotation.
地球倾角发生了巨大偏转
Come on Doctor.
加油, 博士
There aren't that many alternatives. Gigantic heat loss, eh? Er.
并没有太多可能啊。巨额的热量流失, 嗯？呃
I asked for an answer, not a question. Twelve seconds left.
我要的是答案, 不是问题。只剩20秒了
Oh. Er. Oh well. Ahem. In that case the answer's simple. A severe drop in the carbon dioxide level in the Earth's lower atmosphere. Is that it?
哦, 呃, 好了, 嗯, 这样的话答案就很简单了。在地球大气层的下层突然二氧化碳的量急剧降低, 是这个不
翻译备注: ionisation 这个词语本来是指”电离“, 但剧里只是借了这个词, 跟”电离“没有半点关系, 所以翻译为”离子化“
I would use ionisation.
我会采用离子化手段
Well, is he right?
诶, 他对了没？
Yes, he is.
是的, 他对了
But I still don't understand.
但我还是不明白
Well the carbon dioxide level in the Earth's atmosphere helps retain the suns heat. Take that gas away, and there's a sudden freeze up.
地球大气中的二氧化碳会有助于让地球保持从太阳得到的热量。如果这种气体没了, 就会陡然冷下来
Oh, where does the gas go to?
哦, 那些气体去哪儿了
Well...
这个就。。。
You know how efficient our civilisation is, thanks to the direction of the great world computer.
你知道我们的文明是如何有效率的, 这要感谢伟大的世界级电脑给出的方向
And you also know how we conquered the problem of world famine a century ago by artificial food.
而且你也知道我们如何在一个世纪前用人工食物征服了粮食不足的问题
On the land that was once used to grow the food we needed, we built up-to-date living units, to house the ever-increasing population.
在那些以前用来种植粮食的土地上, 我们建立了一些新型的房子, 以让日益增加的人口有地方住
Up to date?
新型的？
Well there were exceptions, of course. I mean this house was classified as being historic interest.
这里有一些例外, 不可避免的。我是说这些房子是分类的, 由于一些历史上原因。
So, the amount of growing plants on the planet, was reduced to an absolute minimum.
于是, 这个星球上生长的作物, 总量就降低了历史最低点
No plants, no carbon dioxide.
没有植物, 就没有二氧化碳
Then suddenly, one year, there was no spring.
然后突然, 某一年, 就没有了春天
Even then it wasn't understood. Not until the ice-caps began to advance.
即使那时我们也还没明白, 直到冰山开始推进
Er, but er, what's this ioniser?
呃, 但是, 这个离子器是什么
Um, Miss Garrett.
唔, Garrett 小姐
lonisation is a method of intensifying the suns heat onto the Earth, but into particular areas.
离子化是一种增强太阳光能量的方法, 用在地球上特定地区
Yeah, it's like a magnifying glass, Jamie.
是的, 就像放大镜一样, Jamie
Oh, aye.
哦, 是
You mean you can melt glaciers and change the weather?
你的意思是你可以融化冰川, 改变气候？
Um, when certain difficulties are overcome.
嗯, 只要某些困难得以解决
Precise control is not easy.
精细控制并不容易
We can't afford to make mistakes. lonisation can produce temperatures intense enough to melt rock.
我们负担不起犯错误的代价的。离子化可以产生足够高的温度，石头都可以溶掉
Only by maintaining a perfect balance can we prevent widespread flooding.
但只有维持一个绝妙的平衡, 我们才可能不被洪水淹没
Can't your computers solve the problem of control?
你的电脑能够解决控制的问题吗？
Of course they can!
它们当然能
Well?
哦？
When the input data is complete they will give us the solution.
只要输入的数据是完整的, 它们就能给出解决方案
Oh, I see. And when will that be?
哦, 明白了。估计是什么时候？
Soon Doctor, soon.
快了, 博士, 快了
What's the position now?
现在处于什么位置？
Well we're barely holding the glacier in check. Now there you see a world map of the situation at the moment.
我们勉强遏制住了冰川。现在你可以看到一幅当前的世界地图
And there you see what's, erm, going on in our sector. But if we fail, then not only will Europe be swallowed up,
在这里你可以看到, 在我们这个区域正在发生的情况。如果我们失败, 不仅仅欧洲会被吞掉
but the balance of power will be ruined, and the whole world program will, will go under.
而且力量会失去平衡, 整个世界的计划就泡汤了。。。
And the glaciers will win.
然后冰山就胜利了
My senior scientist Penley, is missing. I think you have the capabilities to join us here. This great mission. Will you help us?
我的高级科学家 Penley , 消失了。我觉得你有这个能力加入我们, 加入这个伟大的任务。你会帮我们吗？
Well I, I'm willing to try.
好, 我愿意试试
Jolly good. Jolly good. Er, Miss Garrett will give you some background information. You've worked with computers, I presume?
太好了, 太好了。额, Garrett 会给你一些背景信息。你用过电脑吧, 我猜？
Er, only when I have to.
呃, 只是需要的时候
Well Miss Garrett is our computer specialist, she'll help you.
那好 Garrett 小姐是我们的电脑专家, 她会帮助你的
Oh, I'll try and remember that.
哦, 我会试试, 记住了
Here we are completely computerised.
我们这里已经完全电脑化了
Oh never mind.
哦, 别提这个
Every decision is checked, to eliminate risk of failure.
Because of course, all decisions, all actions, must conform to the common good.
每个决策都要核查, 以消除可能失败的风险。
因为所有决策, 所有行动, 当然必须要符合大多数人的利益
This way, gentlemen, this way. Right.
这边, 先生们, 这边。对了
Now do be careful. 'Round here. Steady with her.
现在请小心点, 转角, 稳住
Is this... your full co-operation, Arden? How do you expect us to carry out this...
这。。就是你的全面合作，Arden？你怎么能指望我们能。。。
Great heavens.
老天啊
Yes, I thought you'd be impressed Clent.
Right chaps, lets have him over here...
是的我想你会印象深刻的，Clent。来小伙子们，我们把他停在这儿。。。
This way, this way...
这边，这边。。。
What is it?
这是什么？
It looks like a Viking warrior. Look at the helmet.
看起来像是一个维京战士，看看这个头盔
Frozen for centuries in the ice. Perfectly preserved. Hm, that's odd though.
在冰里冻了好多个世纪。保存得相当完好。唔，这有点奇怪
What? Who are you?
干什么，你是谁？
An addition to our staff, Arden. What's odd Doctor?
我们团队新增的一员，Arden。有什么奇怪的吗，博士？
Well the helmet, it's wrong. When this man was frozen to death only primitive cavemen existed.
哦这个头盔，不对劲。这个人被冻死的时候，只应该有初等的穴居人存在
Well I say it's an undiscovered civilisation. Think of the implications!
我就说是一个从未被发现的文明吧。想想这隐含的是什么！
Well whatever the implications, it must still take second place to out ioniser project.
We have our daily planning conference in three minutes fifteen seconds, exactly.
不管这隐含的是什么，它也得让道于我们的离子器项目。我们还有3分钟就要开每日进展会议了，确切地说，3分15秒
Come along Arden! Play with your toy after the meeting.
过来 Arden ，开完会再来玩你的玩具吧
Well, what's supposed to happen, Doctor?
接下来可能发生什么，博士？
You see this fellow Arden has set the electricity so that the ice melts very slowly, allowing for the resistance.
你看，Arden 这个家伙设定了低电压，以让这些冰融化得很慢，这也带来了阻抗(?)
It's working quite quickly.
但它化得很快
Well, I suspect there are some impurities in the ice. I say.
哦，我怀疑冰里面有一些杂质
Look at that.
看那个
What is it?
是什么
It's an electronic connection. I'm sure of it.
是个电路连接，我敢肯定
It can't be.
不可能
Now you wait here, and, and don't touch anything.
你们先在这里等着，并且，并且什么都不要碰
What's got into him all of a sudden?
他突然这是怎么了
I don't know. Scientists are all alike, eureka and all that.
我不知道，科学家都差不多，一惊一乍的
Aye. Could do with a go on this, maybe.
是啊．(?)
Er, Victoria.
呃，Victoria
What?
什么？
You see how those lassies were dressed?
你看见这里的女士们都是怎么穿着的吗？
Yes I did. And trust you to think of something like that.
是的我看见了，知道你会想这样的问题
What? Couldn't help thinking about it.
什么？忍不住就会想这个问题
Well I think it's disgusting, wearing that kind of thing.
诶，我觉得恶心，戴着那样的东西
Oh, aye, so it is, so it is. You er, you don't see yourself dressed like that then?
哦，是这样，是这样。你，你不想看看自己穿上那样是什么样子？
Jamie!
Oh, I'm sorry, it was just an idea.
哦，抱歉，只是个想法而已
We will now change the subject, please. I want to look at this man.
我们谈点别的吧，求你了。我想看看这个家伙